Dare Adewuyi

42, Teniola Street, Ijeshatedo, Surulere, Lagos, Nigeria Cell: +23407038808765 email : drdre4life2001@yahoo.com

Personal statement

A highly motivated and creative software developer with experience in a variety of exciting projects. A level head and rational approach to problem solving combined with a passion for innovative and fresh ideas has led to a portfolio of impressive web application solutions. Technically competent and industry aware means that each project is undertaken with the most up-to-date and relevant software foundations available.

Core skills

- Knowledge of PHP and Javascript
- Experience with Laravel and Slim frameworks
- Jquery, Vue is framework and Ajax
- Writing efficient queries for large data, ORM
- Experience with object-oriented software development methodologies
- RESTFUL API development and integration
- Cloud Computing (AWS, Digital Ocean)
- GIT
- Working knowledge of Docker

Employment history

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER(PHP) Crednet Technologies(Credpal)- Yaba, Lagos

(December 2018 - till present)

Developing scalable financial applications using software engineering principles and collaborating with other developers to deliver efficient applications serving wide range of users with high conversion rate.

Duties

- Developing new backend services for users and third party clients
- Carrying out code review and ensuring program modules meets the
- Actively participating in every phase of software development life cycle

Accomplishments

- LoanBot Application credit Intelligent credit analysis and and decision
- credpal.com
- Credpal merchant Api

SYSTEM ENGINEER(PHP) Techadavence Limited- VI, Lagos

(September 2017 – November 2018)

Developing new applications with other developers and extending functionalities of existing applications.

Duties

- Understanding and translating requirements into specified software
- Debugging and maintenance of existing applications
- Collaborating with other developers to solve problems
- Writing multiple code and script and ensuring cross browser compliance

Accomplishments

- ERP software design and development
- Bus booking and fleet management application
- Third party payment integration
- Mobile money solution

Freelance PHP Developer

(December 2015 – August 2017)

Leading a small team on a variety of development projects and delivering solutions for organizations and meet and exceed clients' briefs.

Duties

- Outlining specifications for all backend software requirements
- Hands on development of all projects from genesis to delivery
- Mentoring team members in development and technical progression
- Writing multiple code and script and ensuring cross browser compliance

Systems Officer – QESH Standards limited, Port Harcourt

(June 2015 – November 2015)

Duties

- Building and maintaining PHP applications
- Suggesting software improvements on design and functionality
- Diagnosing and rectifying performance issues
- Creating new applications and functionalities

Web Developer/Tutor - New Covenant School, Port Harcourt

(September 2014 – May 2015)

Duties

- Training students in IT and web development using PHP
- Web development
- Maintain ICT lab
- Maintaining continuity throughout all websites both technically and creatively
- Creating new applications and functionalities

PHP Developer Intern – Bureau of Computer Services office of the Governor, Osogbo

(*January 2012 – December 2012*)

Duties

- Design and development of new websites using PHP,HTML and css
- Suggesting improvements on design and functionality
- Assist in creation of and editing of web and app contents

Education

Osun State University

(2009 - 2013)

BSc in Computer Science

School of Science imesi lle

(2001 - 2003) SSCE

References

Available on request.